<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Alejandro Andirkó on Alejandro Andirkó</title>
    <link>/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Alejandro Andirkó on Alejandro Andirkó</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy2019</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 05 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0100</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>EMBL - Reconstructing the Human Past 2019</title>
      <link>/posts/embl19/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/embl19/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Henn, Brenna M., et al. “Clarifying Distinct Models of Modern Human Origins in Africa.” Current Opinion in Genetics &amp;amp; Development, vol. 53, Dec. 2018, pp. 148–56.
&lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1016/j.gde.2018.10.003&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.1016/j.gde.2018.10.003&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Bas-Orth, Carlos, et al. “Synaptic Activity Drives a Genomic Program That Promotes a Neuronal Warburg Effect.” Journal of Biological Chemistry, vol. 292, no. 13, Mar. 2017, pp. 5183–94.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1074/jbc.M116.761106&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.1074/jbc.M116.761106&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;McVicker, Derrick P., et al. “Signaling to the Microtubule Cytoskeleton: An Unconventional Role for CaMKII: CaMKII Signaling to Microtubules.” Developmental Neurobiology, vol. 75, no. 4, Apr. 2015, pp. 423–34.  &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1002/dneu.22227&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.1002/dneu.22227&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Bruner, Emiliano, and Naomichi Ogihara. “Surfin’ Endocasts: The Good and the Bad on Brain Form.” Palaeontologia Electronica, 2018, pp. 1–10. &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.26879/805&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.26879/805&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Xia J, Gill E, &amp;amp; Hancock REW (2015). &lt;em&gt;NetworkAnalyst for Statistical, Visual and Network-based Approaches for Meta-analysis of Expression Data&lt;/em&gt;. Nature Protocols 10, 823–844.
&lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1038/nprot.2015.052&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.1038/nprot.2015.052&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Peyrégne, S, et al. &lt;em&gt;Detecting Ancient Positive Selection in Humans Using Extended Lineage Sorting.&lt;/em&gt; Genome Research, vol. 27, no. 9, Sept. 2017, pp. 1563–72.
&lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.10.1101/gr.219493.116&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;https://doi.10.1101/gr.219493.116&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Racimo, F. “Testing for Ancient Selection Using Cross-Population Allele Frequency Differentiation.” Genetics, vol. 202, no. 2, Feb. 2016, pp. 733–50.
&lt;a href=&#34;https://doi:10.1534/genetics.115.178095&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;https://doi:10.1534/genetics.115.178095&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Goyal, M S, Hawrylycz, M., Miller, J. A., Snyder, A. Z., &amp;amp; Raichle, M. E. (2014). &lt;em&gt;Aerobic glycolysis in the human brain is associated with development and neotenous gene expression&lt;/em&gt;. Cell Metabolism, 19(1), 49–57. &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cmet.2013.11.020&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cmet.2013.11.020&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Kuhlwilm, M, &amp;amp; Boeckx, C (2019). &lt;em&gt;A catalog of single nucleotide changes distinguishing modern humans from archaic hominins&lt;/em&gt;. BioRxiv, 298950. &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1101/298950&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.1101/298950&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Somel, M, Liu, X, &amp;amp; Khaitovich, P. (2013). &lt;em&gt;Human brain evolution: transcripts, metabolites and their regulators&lt;/em&gt;. Nature Reviews Neuroscience, 14(2), 112–127. &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1038/nrn3372&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.1038/nrn3372&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ISLE workshop 2019</title>
      <link>/posts/isle/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/isle/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Enard, W., Gehre, S., Hammerschmidt, K., Hölter, S. M., Blass, T., Somel, M., … Pääbo, S. (2009). &lt;em&gt;A humanized version of foxp2 affects cortico-basal ganglia circuits in mice&lt;/em&gt;. Cell, 137(5), 961–971. &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cell.2009.03.041&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cell.2009.03.041&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Goyal, M. S., Hawrylycz, M., Miller, J. A., Snyder, A. Z., &amp;amp; Raichle, M. E. (2014). &lt;em&gt;Aerobic glycolysis in the human brain is associated with development and neotenous gene expression&lt;/em&gt;. Cell Metabolism, 19(1), 49–57. &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cmet.2013.11.020&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cmet.2013.11.020&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Kuhlwilm, M., &amp;amp; Boeckx, C. (2019). &lt;em&gt;A catalog of single nucleotide changes distinguishing modern humans from archaic hominins&lt;/em&gt;. BioRxiv, 298950. &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1101/298950&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.1101/298950&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Martins, P. T., Marí, M., &amp;amp; Boeckx, C. (2018). &lt;em&gt;SRGAP2 and the gradual evolution of the modern human language faculty&lt;/em&gt;. Journal of Language Evolution, 3(1), 67–78. &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1093/jole/lzx020&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.1093/jole/lzx020&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Somel, M., Liu, X., &amp;amp; Khaitovich, P. (2013). &lt;em&gt;Human brain evolution: transcripts, metabolites and their regulators&lt;/em&gt;. Nature Reviews Neuroscience, 14(2), 112–127. &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1038/nrn3372&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.1038/nrn3372&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>7q11.23 Syndromes Reveal BAZ1B as a Master Regulator of the Modern Human Face and Validate the Self-Domestication Hypothesis</title>
      <link>/publications/baz1b/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publications/baz1b/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A hypothesis concerning how the evolution of prosociality impacted vocal learning</title>
      <link>/talk/isle19/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/talk/isle19/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Derived Homo sapiens cis-eQTL regulation: implications for brain evolution</title>
      <link>/publications/gtex/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publications/gtex/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Oxytocin and Vasopressin Receptor variants as a window onto the evolution of human prosociality</title>
      <link>/publications/oxt/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publications/oxt/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Example Page</title>
      <link>/tutorial/example/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 09 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/tutorial/example/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;In this tutorial, I&amp;rsquo;ll share my top 10 tips for getting started with Academic:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;tip-1&#34;&gt;Tip 1&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;tip-2&#34;&gt;Tip 2&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Privacy Policy</title>
      <link>/privacy/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Jun 2018 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/privacy/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The &#39;guns, germs &amp; steel&#39; underlying Homo Sapiens unique material culture</title>
      <link>/talk/evolang18/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/talk/evolang18/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>EMBL Reconstructing the human past</title>
      <link>/posts/embl_report/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/embl_report/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;EMBL, one of the biggest biology research institutions in the world, has organized a symposium in paleogenomics, and of course the lineup is more than impressive: Svante Pääbo, David Reich, Beth Saphiro and countless of amazing experts were gathering in the impressive, DNA-themed EMBL building in Heidelberg. Sadly, part of the conference overlapped with the American Association of Physical Anthropologist meeting, the biggest gathering of experts having to do with Human Evolution [^1]. Still, the event managed to address a very wide range of topics, from Neanderthal genetics to pioneer methodologies in aDNA, but also leaving room to recent history studies, pathogens and domestication research.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;double_helix.jpeg&#34; alt=&#34;Thematic architecture&#34; /&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;public.jpeg&#34; alt=&#34;Public getting prepared&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Me and the rest of the &lt;a href=&#34;http://cbl.ub.edu/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Cognitive Biology of Language&lt;/a&gt; group arrived to Heidelberg the day before. We knew the EMBL building was not in the city but somewhere in the hills around, but we had no clue about where to pick the buses of at what time. Luckily for us, EBML had set up an app to work you through the city, including the full schedule of the conference, a list of attendants and speakers and other utilities. The app managed to be very useful during the next days, not only because I always struggle to keep the paper with the program close to me but because the bus schedule was in your hand at all times. Kudos for that!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The conference started with a keynote by Svante Pääbo, who gave an overview of his work in the field of paleogenomics (which is, on a large extent, also the history of the field itself). I had the luck of watching other talks by Pääbo before, and I knew already that the exciting content always arrives by the end, with the promise of functionally testing the neanderthal versions of several brain-related genes in brain organoids. The buzz around neanderthalized brain organoids has been going on for a while since &lt;a href=&#34;https://science.sciencemag.org/content/360/6395/1284&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;an article&lt;/a&gt; in the Science magazine news section claimed that the group led by A. Muotri is working on it; whenever it&amp;rsquo;s done is going to be a landmark for the understanding of Neanderthal cognition, and I&amp;rsquo;m sure Pääbo, who is not so far away from retirement, would love to put a final ribbon to his already highly influential career.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another of the ways people are trying to figure out phenotypical effects of the Neanderthal genome is through introgressed sections in modern human populations. Joshua Akey&amp;rsquo;s talk, for example, addressed how they used the UK Biobank to link these alleles to phenotypes, finding interesting things such as a higher risk of depression, among other things [^2]. A new high-coverage Neanderthal genome from Chagyrskaya in preparation for publication might shed new light into potential windows for functional testing [^3]&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On the technical side, there was also talk about much expected retrieval of aDNA from sediments, and other technical advances such as new statistical measures that eliminate the need for reference sequences, that can introduce biases into the mapping of DNA readings. Other talks addressed the need, nevertheless, of introducing more diverse african reference sequences to account for the continent&amp;rsquo;s diversity. In fact, Mattias Jakobson&amp;rsquo;s group is trying hard to get recent history aDNA sequences from Africa to account for migration dynamics inside the continent that could affect the kind of simulations that tell us about the emergence of &lt;em&gt;Homo Sapiens&lt;/em&gt; - including the date of emergence [^4]. The day finished with a nice sunset and a conference party.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;sunset.jpeg&#34; alt=&#34;Sunset&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ke Wang
Stonian shit
Icelandinc shit
R Nielsen Bajau
Munch new dates
Introgression PETR
Aurochs
Modern history then
POSTERS1&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;DAY 3
EMBL career training workshop
Car dom
Novembre
Pontus
Jakobson &amp;gt;300 deep african history bantu expansions etc
Americas: Raghavan, Victor Mayar,
POSTERS2&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;DAY 4
Gut microbia
Yersina Pestis
Ludovico: horses (4 pops)
Kaessman: gene expression in humans&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s going to happen again next year!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[^1] By the way, the AAPA had a couple of days ago a session called &amp;lsquo;Deciphering the Denisovans&amp;rsquo; that prompted a lot of activity on Twitter. The session was live-streamed through Facebook, but I assume they will release a recording in Youtube at some point. If you missed it, keep an eye open!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[^2] Check the Cell paper here&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[^3] The full genome is even &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.eva.mpg.de/genetics/genome-projects/chagyrskaya-neandertal/home.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;publicly available&lt;/a&gt; already!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[^4] See Schlebusch&amp;rsquo;s paper from 2017 for an example &lt;a href=&#34;https://science.sciencemag.org/content/358/6363/652&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ESHE 2018 impressions</title>
      <link>/posts/eshe18/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/eshe18/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This year, the 8th European Society of Human Evolution meeting was held in Faro, (south Portugal). In a certain sense, holding a conference in the south of the iberian peninsula, home to the last Neanderthals, could be considered a felt homage to the diversity of the human family tree. The Calpe Museum in Gibraltar holds a parallel conference on Neanderthals, and not to far off, in Rabat, Morocco, the &lt;a href=&#34;http://panaf18.fsoujda.org/en/home/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;PanAf&lt;/a&gt; (PanAfrican Archaeological Association for Prehistory and Related Studies) was taking place. Three major scientific events related to human evolution almost at the same time, to the delight of those following on Twitter - and the chagrin of the ESHE organization.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The fact that there were around 400 attendants allowed to have an overall impression to the field, from lithics to bones and genetics. As a very interdisciplinary cognitive scientist, I was very much satisfied with the diversity of fields represented, all of them offering insights into our history - as we need as much information as we can gather. Underlying most talks was the idea that we can&amp;rsquo;t no longer think about a &amp;lsquo;craddle of humanity&amp;rsquo;, but several, and that this diversity is key to understand our deep evolutionary history. The fossil record shows an incredible range of archaic and modern looking fossils in overlapping time frames, distributed spatially all over the African continent, yet most archaeological research is done at the same old places, like the Afar basin, in Ethiopia. Broadening our horizons means digging in different sites, as the opening lecture by René Bobe emphasized - and the field is taking good note.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It also means understanding better what we have until now. The recent (polemic) redating of some caves in Spain has given back Neanderthals authorship over their art, but also work on classic sites like Skuhl, Turkana or Sima de los Huesos might still offer us new insights on the Homo history. In addition, new methods for old bones are gaining track: a personal highlight is the promising work on proteomics, which might help us identify bones in a non-destructive way (unlike the not so preservation-friendly aDNA recollection). Geometric morphometrics, a more than familiar method for most archaeologists, is being constantly improved, and we had our fair share in the talks and posters, from . I really think some day near morphometric variation will meet genetics, not so far down the road.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On the aDNA note: there has been much buzz in the field about Denny, the famous Neanderthal-Denisovan hybrid found recently by the team led by Viviane Slon and Svante Pääbo, and it was exciting to hear a bit more about this very lucky finding (you can read a great post by Viviane just &lt;a href=&#34;https://natureecoevocommunity.nature.com/posts/38064-ancient-encounters-how-we-came-across-the-daughter-of-a-neandertal-and-a-denisovan}&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Expect exciting findings like this in future conference reports!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Slides</title>
      <link>/slides/example-slides/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/slides/example-slides/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h1 id=&#34;welcome-to-slides&#34;&gt;Welcome to Slides&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://sourcethemes.com/academic/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Academic&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;features&#34;&gt;Features&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Efficiently write slides in Markdown&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;3-in-1: Create, Present, and Publish your slides&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Supports speaker notes&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Mobile friendly slides&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;controls&#34;&gt;Controls&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Next: &lt;code&gt;Right Arrow&lt;/code&gt; or &lt;code&gt;Space&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Previous: &lt;code&gt;Left Arrow&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Start: &lt;code&gt;Home&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Finish: &lt;code&gt;End&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Overview: &lt;code&gt;Esc&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Speaker notes: &lt;code&gt;S&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fullscreen: &lt;code&gt;F&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Zoom: &lt;code&gt;Alt + Click&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/hakimel/reveal.js#pdf-export&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;PDF Export&lt;/a&gt;: &lt;code&gt;E&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;code-highlighting&#34;&gt;Code Highlighting&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Inline code: &lt;code&gt;variable&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Code block:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-python&#34;&gt;porridge = &amp;quot;blueberry&amp;quot;
if porridge == &amp;quot;blueberry&amp;quot;:
    print(&amp;quot;Eating...&amp;quot;)
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;math&#34;&gt;Math&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In-line math: $x + y = z$&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Block math:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;$$
f\left( x \right) = \;\frac{{2\left( {x + 4} \right)\left( {x - 4} \right)}}{{\left( {x + 4} \right)\left( {x + 1} \right)}}
$$&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;fragments&#34;&gt;Fragments&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Make content appear incrementally&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;{{% fragment %}} One {{% /fragment %}}
{{% fragment %}} **Two** {{% /fragment %}}
{{% fragment %}} Three {{% /fragment %}}
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Press &lt;code&gt;Space&lt;/code&gt; to play!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;fragment &#34; &gt;
   One
&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&#34;fragment &#34; &gt;
   &lt;strong&gt;Two&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&#34;fragment &#34; &gt;
   Three
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A fragment can accept two optional parameters:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;class&lt;/code&gt;: use a custom style (requires definition in custom CSS)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;weight&lt;/code&gt;: sets the order in which a fragment appears&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;speaker-notes&#34;&gt;Speaker Notes&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Add speaker notes to your presentation&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-markdown&#34;&gt;{{% speaker_note %}}
- Only the speaker can read these notes
- Press `S` key to view
{{% /speaker_note %}}
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Press the &lt;code&gt;S&lt;/code&gt; key to view the speaker notes!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;aside class=&#34;notes&#34;&gt;
  &lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Only the speaker can read these notes&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Press &lt;code&gt;S&lt;/code&gt; key to view&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/aside&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;themes&#34;&gt;Themes&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;black: Black background, white text, blue links (default)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;white: White background, black text, blue links&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;league: Gray background, white text, blue links&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;beige: Beige background, dark text, brown links&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;sky: Blue background, thin dark text, blue links&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;night: Black background, thick white text, orange links&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;serif: Cappuccino background, gray text, brown links&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;simple: White background, black text, blue links&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;solarized: Cream-colored background, dark green text, blue links&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;


&lt;section data-noprocess data-shortcode-slide
  
      
      data-background-image=&#34;/img/boards.jpg&#34;
  &gt;


&lt;h2 id=&#34;custom-slide&#34;&gt;Custom Slide&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Customize the slide style and background&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-markdown&#34;&gt;{{&amp;lt; slide background-image=&amp;quot;/img/boards.jpg&amp;quot; &amp;gt;}}
{{&amp;lt; slide background-color=&amp;quot;#0000FF&amp;quot; &amp;gt;}}
{{&amp;lt; slide class=&amp;quot;my-style&amp;quot; &amp;gt;}}
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;custom-css-example&#34;&gt;Custom CSS Example&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let&amp;rsquo;s make headers navy colored.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Create &lt;code&gt;assets/css/reveal_custom.css&lt;/code&gt; with:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-css&#34;&gt;.reveal section h1,
.reveal section h2,
.reveal section h3 {
  color: navy;
}
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;questions&#34;&gt;Questions?&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://discourse.gohugo.io&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Ask&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://sourcethemes.com/academic/docs/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Documentation&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
