<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Logs on Alejandro M. Andirkó</title>
    <link>https://andirko.eu/log/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Logs on Alejandro M. Andirkó</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 10 Jan 2022 16:38:37 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://andirko.eu/log/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Album listening log</title>
      <link>https://andirko.eu/log/listening/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Jan 2022 16:38:37 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://andirko.eu/log/listening/</guid>
      <description>Album listening log  Hearing is a labor like reading Hearing is a labor like keeping still  The ideal goal is 365 albums at the end of the year. A more realistic figure given past years is between 100 and 200 ambums, when work allows. Depending on the circumstances I might take break periods where I listen to loose songs instead and try and catch up in other weeks.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bass exercises</title>
      <link>https://andirko.eu/log/electric_bass/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Jan 2022 16:38:37 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://andirko.eu/log/electric_bass/</guid>
      <description>Bass I&amp;rsquo;m recording here the progress I do with bass playing.
2022 Goals Improvisation
 Better understanding and comfort with altered dominant tensions. 20 iterations, all keys.  8/20 it. ████_____ 40%
Technical
 Modal sequences 90 bpm  1/20 it. █_________ 10%
Repertoire
 Fluid walking over the first section of Body and soul. 20 iterations, all keys  0/20 it.  _________ 0%
Rhythm
 Polymuting exercise 01. 120 bpm  0/120 it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Projects and meta</title>
      <link>https://andirko.eu/log/general/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Jan 2022 16:38:37 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://andirko.eu/log/general/</guid>
      <description>Why log?
 2022 00F01 Climate change protest action.
   00D01 General, ongoing populating the wiki. Started involving myself more in climate change activism.
00C04 Started new job as a developer.
00A00 Started seriously considering logging. Started website revamp. Considered several personal wiki/memex posibilities.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Reading list</title>
      <link>https://andirko.eu/log/reading/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Jan 2022 16:38:37 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://andirko.eu/log/reading/</guid>
      <description>Books I&amp;rsquo;ll list here my current reading list. I have to admit it&amp;rsquo;s not my priority activity these days, prefering music overall. I tend to read essays, not much fiction. I&amp;rsquo;m also in a strike of eco-related readings right now.
I tend to read several things at the same time, and leave and retake topics as my intest demands.
I&amp;rsquo;m currently reading: Dilla Time - Dan Charnas  ██______ ~20%</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
